A Guide to the Papers of the Carter and Wellford Family of Sabine Hall 1650-1918
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series III: Papers of Landon Carter
  - Landon Carter "To the Members of the Late House of Representatives of Massachusetts Bay" 1768 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Piece by Landon Carter on the Townshend Acts (fragment) 1768 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Opening portion of "Treatise on Agriculture" by Landon Carter [1768] (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Landon Carter's Petition "to the several inhabitants of the County of Richmond against dividing the counties from river to river" 1769 October (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Landon Carter to the "Honorable Speaker and Gentlemen of the House of Burgesses" (copy) 1769 October (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Minutes of a Meeting of the Committee of Richmond County respecting the Association for American Freedom 1774 October 27 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - "His Majesty's Most Gracious Speech from the Throne" 1774 December 1 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - "Announcement of Selection of Delegates to the Continental Congress by the Freeholders of Richmond County" 1774 December 5 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Landon Carter to "The Independent Company or Company of Volunteers of Richmond County" 1775 April 28 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Landon Carter to unknown recipient [British] 1775 April & May (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Landon Carter's poem "Addressed to Sleep" 1775 August 17 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Griffith to Landon Carter-lampoon on George III and Lord Dunmore 1755 August (Box-folder 2:3)
  - John Sydnor's census: "A List of Souls Alive in the Forks of Totusky 1775" 1775 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Rough draft of a piece by Landon Carter on the dispute between the Mother Country and the Colonies, including Boston Port Bill (fragment) 1775-1776 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Rough draft of a piece by Landon Carter on the refusal to join an association (fragment) 1775-1776 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Note by Landon Carter regretting the strife between England and America 1775-1776 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - "A List of Acts Passed in Assembly May and June 1777" 1777 June (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Landon Carter to "The Worshipful the Court Martial of Richmond County" 1777 October 22 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Landon Carter's Observations on the Surrender of Burgoyne to Gate post 1777 October (Box-folder 2:5)
  - "Proposal to Establish a School in Lunenberg Parish in the County of Richmond" ante 1779 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Landon Carter's medical observations ante 1779 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Landon Carter's suggestion for making a harness for a horse or oxen ante 1779 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Epitaph for a friend ante 1779 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Landon Carter's essay on the cultivation of hops 1779 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Landon Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter and Francis Lightfoot Lee 1770s (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Verses... on the speaker of audit answer n.d. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Series IV: Diary of Landon Carter
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1763 November 15-1764 December 15 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1770 January 5-31 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1770 February 6-28 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1770 March 1-31 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1770 April 1-30 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1770 May 1-31 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1770 June 19-28 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1770 July 1-28 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1770 August 2-September 8 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1770 September 8-October 13 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1770 October 13-November 9 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1770 November 10-25 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1770 December 3-1771 January 18 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1771 January 18-February 26 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1771 February 26-April 9 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1771 April 17-30 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1771 June 1-29 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1771 July 1-31 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1771 August 2-24 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1771 September 5-25 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1771 November 6-December 31 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1772 January 8-April 1 (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1772 April 2-30 (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1772 May 6-July 23 (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1772 August 1-September 2 (Box-folder 2:12)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1772 September 4-October 7 (Box-folder 2:12)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1772 October 9-25 (Box-folder 2:12)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1773 June 1-29 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1773 September 1-October 3 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1774 February 1-March 1 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1774 May 1-30 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1774 June 3-29 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1774 August 3-September 4 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1774 October 1-17 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1774 October 17-31 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1774 December 1-31 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1775 July 3-31 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1775 September 2-30 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1776 January 31-March 1 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1776 March 1-31 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1776 April 1-26 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1776 May 1-15 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1776 July 3-5, 25 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1777 February 3-28 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1777 April 1-30 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1777 July 6-August 15 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1777 August 31-October 4 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1778 August 1-September 2 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Diary of Landon Carter 1778 September 10-October 2 (Box-folder 3:7)
- Series V: Correspondence of Robert Wormeley Carter
  - Carter Ludlow to Robert Wormeley Carter 1780 November 4 (Box-folder 3:8)
    patriotism; American army; French army; British army; John André Benedict Arnold; Revolution
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Thomas Bryan Martin 1784 April 12 (Box-folder 3:8)
    discharging debts
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Gabriel Jones (copy) 1788 May 29 (Box-folder 3:8)
    Landon Carter estate
  - Henry "Light Horse Harry" Lee to Robert Wormeley Carter 1792 March 16 (Box-folder 3:8)
    bond held by W. Fitzhugh; fishing in the Rappahannock and the James River
  - Margaret Kelly to Robert Wormeley Carter 1797 October 25 (Box-folder 3:8)
    requests money for passage to her native country
  - Elizabeth Ford to Robert [Wormeley] Carter 1800 June 22 (Box-folder 3:9)
    widow of James Ford; details family woes; requests money
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter [1803] (Box-folder 3:9)
    discusses the constitution, presidential caucus, Electoral College, principles of government
  - Ann Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter ca. 1803 (Box-folder 3:9)
    birth of little sister
  - Landon Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1813 February 5 (Box-folder 3:9)
    advice on education and ladies; instructions to buy a coach in Lancaster
  - Landon Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter, with postscript from mother and sister 1813 February 21 (Box-folder 3:9)
    advice on establishing character and the temptations faced; specifications for a coach to be bought by his son; raising a company of cavalry; British army
  - Landon Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1814 July 30 (Box-folder 3:9)
    retreating to Clermont; evacuation of slaves from Sabine Hall to the upper country
  - Landon Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1815 January 16 (Box-folder 3:9)
    epidemic; death of Senator Richard Brent; family news
  - Landon Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter ante 1820 August 11 (Box-folder 3:9)
    leaving Fredericksburg; poor health
  - St. Leger L. Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1821 October 6 (Box-folder 3:9)
    humor regarding the latter's upcoming marriage to Mary Walker Carter
  - Mary L. Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1825 January 8 (Box-folder 3:9)
    practicality of trip to Richmond; upcoming marriage of Mary Berkeley Minor to [William Mathews] Blackford; value of Jessy
  - Wright P. Southall to Robert Wormeley Carter, attached to broadside, "Public Meetings in the Borough of Norfolk" 1835 February. 12 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Armistead L. Wellford to Robert Wormeley Carter 1836 January 5 (Box-folder 3:10)
    Dr. Archer; improvements that will be highly beneficial to this section of our State
  - John Tyler to Robert Wormeley Carter 1836 January 7 (Box-folder 3:10)
    copy-original in Autograph Collection; Jackson's fiscal policies; Virginia; violation of the Constitution; Benjamin Watkins Lee; current resolutions
  - Wright P. Southall to Robert Wormeley Carter 1836 February 12 (Box-folder 3:10)
    on broadside "Public Meeting in the Borough of Norfolk"
  - John S. Wellford to Robert Wormeley Carter 1836 February 17 (Box-folder 3:10)
    establishment of a new bank in Fredericksburg to provide more capital for public improvement and individual enterprise
  - J. A. Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1839 May 14 (Box-folder 3:10)
    Rebecca Dulaney and her education and guardianship; Mr. Daingerfield
  - Anne Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1841 November 12 (Box-folder 3:11)
    children's recovery from measles
  - Elizabeth Landon Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1842 January 23 (Box-folder 3:11)
    family news; dental work; grandmother's birthday celebration on January 17th; Madame Paolina Bonaparte in attendance; lessons in school and piano; Charles Carroll and his daughter, Violetta
  - Anne Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1842 February 2 (Box-folder 3:11)
    daughters attending dancing school; Mr. [John Quincy] Adams
  - Robert E. Lee to Robert Wormeley Carter 1842 February 10, R. E. Lee Collection (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Rebecca Dulaney to Robert Wormeley Carter 1842 February 16 (Box-folder 3:11)
    burning of Shute's Hill near Alexandria; spending summer in London with Uncle Armistead Carter; Mr. Daingerfield
  - Elizabeth Landon Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1842 May 24 (Box-folder 3:11)
    party at the Rives' home with Emily [Amelie] and Ella; piano lessons; Methodist Preacher Stanley from Alabama
  - Ann Catharine Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1842 December 4 (Box-folder 3:11)
    French studies; family news
  - Ann Catharine Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1843 February 9 (Folder 3:11)
    wedding of Lane Lomax and Sarah Barnard; living with grandmother; Octagon House
  - John Tyler to Robert Wormeley Carter ca. 1843 (Box-folder 3:11)
    copy-original in Vault, Autograph Collection; requests his attendance at dinner
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1851 March 31 (Box-folder 3:12)
    provides character letter for Armistead Wellford and family as suitable for marriage to Carter's daughter; sowed clover-seed; Bishop Meade; Edward McGuire
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1851 April 18 (Box-folder 3:12)
    dispute between the families; effect on his daughter's happiness
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1851 November 13 (Box-folder 3:12)
    arrangement to procure a suitable house and lot in Fredericksburg for his daughter's comfort; offer to reside in his home
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Armistead Nelson Wellford post 1851 November 13 (Box-folder 3:12)
    suitable home for his daughter
  - Robert W. Conrad to Robert Wormeley Carter 1851 December 19 (Box-folder 3:12)
    expresses surprise and concern over Carter relaying an accusation that he was inhospitable to Messrs. Conrad and Faulkner; discusses their many communications and the intent to get together; the Whig Convention of Baltimore in 1844; the current political torrent, with John Janney being defeated in Loudoun County and Jefferson electing two democrats to the House of Delegates; negative comments on his expected results of the Virginia Reform Convention
  - Charles James Faulkner to Robert Wormeley Carter 1851 December 22 (Box-folder 3:12)
    expresses surprise over the charge that Carter had been inhospitable to Mr. Conrad or himself; Whig Convention of Baltimore in 1840; claims that Carter has always been very open in extending invitations to visit
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to W. R. Mason 1852 February 28 (Box-folder 3:12)
    relaying that he had been informed that Mason had circulated a report of Carter's inhospitality; denying any occasion where he treated Messrs. Conrad and Faulkner with anything less than respect and kindness, claiming it to be false and malicious
  - Elizabeth Landon Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1853 March 18 (Box-folder 3:12)
    Anderson's performances; Sabine Hall; Villette by Charlotte Bronte
  - Elizabeth Landon Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1853 June 6 (Box-folder 3:12)
    Baptist association in session; Dr. Bacon and his wife
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1854 January 12 (Box-folder 3:13)
    winter storm; State Society [of the Agricultural and Mechanical Society]; guano monopoly; Southern Planter
  - George W. Lewis to Robert Wormeley Carter 1854 April 24 (Box-folder 3:13)
    Tayloe lawsuit; difficulties with Ogle Tayloe; statesmen Clay, Webster, and Calhoun
  - Virginia Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1854 June 13 (Box-folder 3:13)
    death of Mrs. Lomax
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1854 June 21 (Box-folder 3:13)
    Rappahannock River Agricultural and Mechanical Society; request for Carter to address their annual meeting; wheat and corn crops
  - Virginia Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1854 September 20 (Box-folder 3:13)
    dispute between the families over the settlement of the estate; family news
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to William Webb, Jr. 1854 October 13 (Box-folder 3:13)
    land dispute with W. Henry Tayloe
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1854 November 24 (Box-folder 3:13)
    law suites; dispute between the legatees and his father's executors; past settlements
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1855 February 5 (Box-folder 3:14)
    desire to reduce debts; dispute between the families; plan of arbitration proposed by Judge Lomax; contested claim of interest; payment to Dr. Wellford
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1855 March 1 (Box-folder 3:14)
    draft owed Carter from Benjamin Ogle Tayloe; delay in the arbitration due to Carter's withdrawal of assent
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Edward Thornton Tayloe 1855 March 3 (Box-folder 3:14)
    reasons for not uniting in the proposal for arbitration
  - Robert Eden Scott to Robert Wormeley Carter 1855 April 9 (Box-folder 3:14)
    intention to examine the census of the defendants in the case; proposal of Judge Lomax; opinion on law suit
  - Armistead Nelson Wellford to Robert Wormeley Carter 1855 May 24 (Box-folder 3:14)
    health of "Lizzie" [Elizabeth Landon Carter] Wellford following childbirth of second child; son Carter
  - Virginia Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1855 June 25 (Box-folder 3:14)
    death of mother Virginia Tayloe with herself, Benjamin Ogle Tayloe and his wife, Lewis (their old servant) in attendance; request their presence at the funeral
  - W. Henry Tayloe to Edward Thornton Tayloe, with letter from E. T. Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1855 June 26 (Box-folder 3:14)
    Carter's reluctance to change position concerning law suit; actions preventing his brother's invitation to attend their mother's funeral; "restoration of miserable, personal relations"
  - Virginia Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1855 November 9 (Box-folder 3:14)
    [inquiries about the family; feelings about moving from Octagon House, Washington, D. C. to Virginia Place; effects on the family of George W. Lewis while he is sent on a three year cruise; settlement of an account with Mr. Scott; limited accommodations for herself and her sister, Anne, and her children
  - John A. Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1855 December 10 (Box-folder 3:14)
    Senator, their thoroughbred horse; the latter's health
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Bishop [William] Meade 1855 (Box-folder 3:14)
    Meade's history of the Episcopal Church [Old churches, ministers and families of Virginia]; gleanings, recollections, anecdotes and descriptions of their church and its people; Reverends Isaac William Giberne and George Young; purchase of the family Massey silver vessels by John Tayloe and presented to Saint John's Church; influence of the Carter, Tayloe, Lee, and other powerful families; Church in Farnham Parish; Reverend Brockenbrough; Miss McCall's grammar school; time without religious instruction
  - John L. Lackey to Robert Wormeley Carter 1856 January 31 (Box-folder 3:15)
    agreement between the two men concerning Elias working for Lackey, earning journeymen's wages
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to George W. Lewis 1856 April 4 (Box-folder 3:15)
    Col. Tayloe's proposal of the restoration of the social relations of their families; Carter's refusal
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Richmond Whig and clipping 1856 July 21 (Box-folder 3:15)
    declining his nomination to Congress signed by "Essex" in the Whig, with the clipping
  - Fletcher H. Hays to Robert Wormeley Carter 1857 June 18 (Box-folder 3:15)
    egotiation on debt; bad crop year; owns real estate and wishes to sell some of the tracts
  - Sophia Snyder to Robert Wormeley Carter 1857 September [1], 6 (Box-folder 3:15)
    privilege to witness the Christian death of Elizabeth Landon Carter; recollections of her last few days; advice on the treatment of his remaining daughter, Ann, as a rational, sensible woman; determination of their homes and of the boys
  - Sophia Snyder to Robert Wormeley Carter post 1857 September 6 (Box-folder 3:15)
    agrees to undertake Kate's commission
  - Fletcher H. Mays to Robert Wormeley Carter 1857 October 4 (Box-folder 3:15)
    heavy liabilities; portion of debt now liquidated; pressing not to sue him; will give a confession of judgment
  - William P. Palmer to Robert Wormeley Carter 1858 March 12 (Box-folder 3:15)
    elected as life-member of the Virginia Historical Society by nomination of Charles Carter Lee and recommendation of the Executive Committee
  - Fletcher H. Hays to Robert Wormeley Carter 1858 June 15 (Box-folder 3:15)
    acceptance of proposition
  - Armistead Nelson Wellford to Robert Wormeley Carter 1858 December 27 (Box-folder 3:15)
    news of the children, Carter and Randolph; news of Richmond and "the number of negroes, who fill the streets..."
  - Armistead Nelson Wellford to Robert Wormeley Carter 1859 January 20 (Box-folder 3:15)
    auction sale of stocks of local estates; expected large attendance at the Convention; news of the children, Carter and Randolph
  - James M. Herndon to Robert Wormeley Carter 1859 February 14 (Box-folder 3:15)
    Bank of Commerce business; agreement between Carter and Mays; suggests getting a deed of trust for the tract
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Fletcher H. Mays 1859 May 21 (Box-folder 3:15)
    sent statement of interest due; requests deed of trust on the stock sold
  - F. B. Miller to Robert Wormeley Carter 1860 January 13 (Box-folder 3:15)
    Mays requested negotiation which failed
  - F. B. Miller to Robert Wormeley Carter 1860 February 4 (Box-folder 3:15)
    Hays has given a confession of judgment; struggling to relieve himself of debt
  - F. B. Miller to Robert Wormeley Carter 1860 July 22 (Box-folder 3:15)
    Carter has deed of trust for tract of land on James River
  - John A. Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter 1861 September 30 (Box-folder 3:15)
    concern for brother's health; Shelby's promotion; note to John Minor about 'Kit Kat' post rates; sons in the Army; Richard H. Dulaney; "death of poor Washington, killed under Gen. Lee..." and earlier death of his wife, daughter of Wilson Seldon of Exeter, leaving eight orphans; death of Robert Armistead, leaving his wife and three daughters alone in Arkansas
- Series VI: Correspondence of Armistead Nelson Wilford
  - Copies of correspondence relative to a quarrel between Dr. Robert Wellford and Francis Thornton 1800 (Box-folder 3:16)
    arising from an accusation of desertion from the British Army in 1778 by the latter against the former
  - Edward C. Marshall to George W. Lewis 1862 January 16 (Box-folder 3:17)
    debt owed to the Carter estate
  - James Marshall to George W. Lewis 1862 January 17 (Box-folder 3:17)
    promises payments on debt owed to the Carter estate
  - R. H. Maury to George W. Lewis 1862 January 30 (Box-folder 3:17)
    Col. Carter advanced money to Caperton, Morton and himself for the bonds to be used by the R. H. Maury & Company
  - Robert S. Hipkins to George W. Lewis 1862 February 4 (Box-folder 3:17)
    debts owed to the Carter estate; payment schedule; has some old rum in his possession belonging to the estate
  - Charles C. Wellford to George W. Lewis 1862 February 4 (Box-folder 3:17)
    inconvenient to pay on small note to Col. Carter having just bought a furnace property
  - S. S. Hutt to [George W. Lewis] 1862 February 6 (Box-folder 3:17)
    debt paid last July
  - James Marshall to George W. Lewis 1862 February 8 (Box-folder 3:17)
    evidence of payment to Col. Carter on September 6,1861
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1865 September 25 (Box-folder 3:17)
    notice to the debtors of the estate to pay interest
  - James Marshall to George W. Lewis 1865 September 27 (Box-folder 3:17)
    interest on bond due to the Carter estate; ability to make payment depends on selling land; laws on interest
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1865 October 21 (Box-folder 3:17)
    suggestions toward the settlement of the Ward debt; deed of trust upon negroes; suggestion to expedite his qualification as guardian for his eldest son, thereby having the Sabine Hall real estate solely under his control; separation of profits of the land stock and the personal estate
  - Edward C. Marshall to George W. Lewis 1865 October 26 (Box-folder 3:17)
    interest on bond due to the Carter estate; war has left farmers destitute; his financial schemes depended on the success of the Confederacy; has crop of wheat and cattle; mentions Willoughby Newton; recent elections of Conrad, Stewart and Benjamin Johnson Barbour
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1865 December 25 (Box-folder 3:17)
    debts owed to the Carter estate
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1866 May 21 (Box-folder 3:17)
    court obligations; suggestion of obtaining judgments in debt cases where debtors own land; advises him to make an inventory of the personal estate to which Carter is entitled; legal requirements
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1866 June 15 (Box-folder 3:17)
    list of bonds for taxation; debts owed to the Carter estate
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1866 September 26 (Box-folder 3:17)
    principal of the debts; difficulty in ascertaining payments made and balances due; promissory note from F. H. Mays
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1866 November 7 (Box-folder 3:17)
    concern over a matter in the administration of the estate of Col. Carter; conversion of State Stocks to Confederate securities; cases where executors involving infants may be held liable for change of investments
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1867 January 14 (Box-folder 3:18)
    Judge Lomax's debt to the Carter estate; proposal to sell the certificates of interest of Kate Carter's Virginia Stock; Kate's health; severe winter; mention of sensational trial and impeachment of President Andrew Johnson; note from W. S. Barton